Finding aid for Walter W. Marquardt Papers, 1896-1952
Bentley Historical Library
Walter W. Marquardt papers
1896-1952
Bentley Historical Library
Marquardt, Walter W. (Walter William), 1878-
91421 Aa 2
8 linear feet
446 MB (online)
Educator and director of education 1916-1919 in the Philippines. Bound volumes containing correspondence, appointments, speeches, writings, diaries, and travel accounts detailing career in the Philippines.
The collection was donated in 1974 by Marquardt's son, Frederic S. Marquardt (donor no. 5131 ).
No further additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Digitization: The Library has undertaken the digitization of a number of sound recordings within this collection. The resulting audio files are available for playback only in the Bentley Library Reading Room. Links to item images and additional information are available within this finding aid. Original sound recordings are only available for staff use.
Walter Marquardt (1878-1962) arrived in the Philippine Islands as a teacher in 1909. He was quickly made a supervising teacher, then high school principal, and eventually Superintendent of Schools for the province of Leyte.
He left Leyte in 1910 when he was made superintendent of the Philippine School of Arts and Trades in Manila. In 1916 he became the head of the entire Philippine school system with the title of Director of Education, remaining in the post until 1919 when he left to take charge of the "pensionado system," in which top Filipino students were sent to the United States at the Philippine government's expense for specialized training.
He gave up his work with the Philippine government in 1923 and was home in the United States on vacation in the summer of 1941.
Walter Marquardt's collection is made up of bound volumes containing correspondence, appointments, speeches, writings, diaries, and travel accounts detailing his career in the Philippines and a collection of 360 hand-colored glass slides. The slides include views of Philippine people, buildings, and scenery, especially of native tribes, and slides of Marquardt and other American officials in the Philippines. The collection also includes one sound cassette of a radio speech, dated February 28, 1945, to be broadcast to the people of the Philippines by the Office of War Information, to mark the liberation of Manila from the Japanese.
Education -- Philippines.; Philippines -- History -- 1898-1946.; Philippines -- History -- 1898-1946.; Philippines -- History -- Japanese occupation, 1942-1945.; World War, 1939-1945 -- Campaigns -- Philippines.; Diaries.; Sound recordings.; Lantern slides.; Photographs.; Marquardt, Walter W. (Walter William), 1878-; Taft, William H. (William Howard), 1857-1930.; Yeater, Charles Emmett, 1861-; Marquardt, Walter W. (Walter William), 1878-; Laurel, Jose P. (Jose Paciano), 1891-1959.; Osmeña, Sergio, 1878-1961.; Romulo, Carlos P. (Carlos Peña), 1899-1985.
- Lantern Slides, 360 slides
  The Lantern slides consist of hand colored slides of Philippine people, buildings, and scenery, especially of native tribes, and slides of Marquardt and other American officials in the Philippines, ca. 1916-1919. The slides are arranged by Topic and each is numbered.
  - Transportation
    - Vinta near Borneo, [1] (Box 1, Tray 1)
    - Truck transportation--Leyte, [2] (Box 1, Tray 1)
    - Another method of transportation to launch in shallow water, [3] (Box 1, Tray 1)
    - Banca or barroto, [4] (Box 1, Tray 1)
    - Bamboo ferry, [5] (Box 1, Tray 1)
    - The river steamer Hall on Cotabato River, [6] (Box 1, Tray 1)
    - Calesa, [7] (Box 1, Tray 1)
    - Carabao and Cart, [8] (Box 1, Tray 1)
    - Water carriers, [9] (Box 1, Tray 1)
    - Pack ponies with pottery, [10] (Box 1, Tray 1)
    - Travel to Antipolo old method, [11] (Box 1, Tray 1)
    - A dug-out ferry, [12] (Box 1, Tray 1)
    - Going to market in Laguna, [13] (Box 1, Tray 1)
    - Ferry near Vigan, [14] (Box 1, Tray 1)
    - Construction on Lucban Road, [15] (Box 1, Tray 1)
  - Flowers
    - Liana, [16] (Box 1, Tray 1)
    - Blooming orchid, [17] (Box 1, Tray 1)
    - Pitcher plant, [18] (Box 1, Tray 1)
    - Rafflesia--largest known flower; 3' diameter, [19] (Box 1, Tray 1)
    - Orchids, [20] (Box 1, Tray 1)
  - Trees
    - Tree fern, [21] (Box 1, Tray 1)
    - Tree ferns, [22] (Box 1, Tray 1)
    - Balete tree, [23] (Box 1, Tray 1)
    - Coconut tree, [24] (Box 1, Tray 1)
    - Tapping a rubber tree, [25] (Box 1, Tray 1)
  - Activities
    - Barrio band, [26] (Box 1, Tray 1)
    - Pounding rice, [27] (Box 1, Tray 1)
    - First cane mill among the Ilongots, [28] (Box 1, Tray 1)
    - Second cane mill, [29] (Box 1, Tray 1)
    - Native blacksmith shop, [30] (Box 1, Tray 1)
    - Bontoc Smith, [31] (Box 1, Tray 1)
    - Selling garden products, [32] (Box 1, Tray 1)
    - Furniture, [33] (Box 1, Tray 1)
    - Locust swarm, [34] (Box 1, Tray 1)
    - A wild carabao killed on Upper Cagayan, [35] (Box 1, Tray 1)
    - Moving a house, [36] (Box 1, Tray 1)
    - Washing clothes, [37] (Box 1, Tray 1)
    - Abaca Press, [38] (Box 1, Tray 1)
    - Hauling logs, [39] (Box 1, Tray 1)
    - Hog raising at Muños, [40] (Box 1, Tray 1)
    - Clean-up Week scene, [41] (Box 1, Tray 1)
  - Places
    - Map of Philippines, [42] (Box 1, Tray 1)
    - Bontoc government building, [43] (Box 1, Tray 1)
    - Bridge on Luzon, [44] (Box 1, Tray 1)
    - Gate--walled city--Manila, [45] (Box 1, Tray 1)
    - River near Manila, [46] (Box 1, Tray 1)
    - Benguet-Baguio Zigzag, 1920; [47] (Box 1, Tray 1)
    - Benguet-rice terraces, [48] (Box 1, Tray 1)
    - Igorot Burial ground, 1919; [49] (Box 1, Tray 1)
    - Igorot burial ground, [50] (Box 1, Tray 1)
    - Bell amphitheater-Camp John Hay-Bagnio, [51] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - A home garden, [52] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - Mt. Mayon, [53] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - Ready to launch a fish trap, [54] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - Government building-Sandacan, Borneo, [55] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - Dock at Zamboanga, [56] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - Igorot village near Bontoc, [57] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - View top of Polis range, [58] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - Rice terraces, Banaue, [59] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - Planting rice terraces, Banaue, [60] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - The top of a terraced hill, Banaue, [61] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - Rice terraces, [62] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - An Ilongot rice granary, [63] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - An Ilongot storehouse, [64] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - A Negrito home, [65] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - Road scene, Bagnio, [66] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - Government center, Bagnio, [67] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - Mirador, [68] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - Flower garden-teachers' camp, [69] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - Vaults, Paco cemetery, [70] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - Maria Cristina Falls, Lanao, [71] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - Pagsanjan Falls, [72] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - Taal volcano and Lake Borbon, [73] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - Taal in eruption, [74] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - Fissures at Lemery, [75] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - Underground river, Palawan, [76] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - Estero scene, Manila, [77] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - Masonic temple, Manila, [78] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - Bilibid Prison, [79] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - Luneta, [80] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - Burnham Green Club buildings, [81] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - Old moat, Parian gate, [82] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - Street, walled city, [83] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - Rice granary, [84] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - Salt springs in Nueva Vizciya, [85] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - Salt beds near Manila, [86] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - Gilbert bridge, Ilocos Norte, [87] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - Street window-walled city, Manila, [88] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - Submarines, Manila, [89] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - Stone staircase, Batangas, [90] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - The Sultan of Sulu's Palace, Jolo, [91] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - Old Fort used as golf club, Jolo, [92] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - Church and plaza, Tagbilaran, Bohol, [93] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - Stone steps leading from beach to church, Bohol, [94] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - The fortress church at Cuyo, Palawan, [95] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - Fortress church, Cuyo, Palawan, [96] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - The fortress church, Cuyo, [97] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - Fortress church Cuyo, Palawan, [98] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - Altar church Oton, Iloilo, [99] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - Church, Badoc, Ilocos Norte, [99a] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - Church Paoay-Ilocos Norte, [100] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - Church, Candon, Ilocos Sur, [101] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - Church steps, Sta. Maria, Ilocos Sur, [102] (Box 1, Tray 2)
    - Church tower, Romblon 1635 15 years after Pilgrims landed, [103] (Box 2, Tray 3)
    - Church image at Vigan, stones are thrown at image for better health, [104] (Box 2, Tray 3)
    - Church used as a school garden, [105] (Box 2, Tray 3)
    - United Brethren (Protestant) Church, Tubao, Union, [106] (Box 2, Tray 3)
    - Cathedral, Manila, [107] (Box 2, Tray 3)
    - Church at Tamauini, Isabela, [108] (Box 2, Tray 3)
    - Church at Kiangan, Mountain Province, [109] (Box 2, Tray 3)
    - Bamboo Pipe Organ, Las Piñas, [110] (Box 2, Tray 3)
    - Sultan's Mosque, Jolo, [111] (Box 2, Tray 3)
    - Baler church, [112] (Box 2, Tray 3)
  - Igorot Tribe
    - Igorot weavers, [113] (Box 2, Tray 3)
    - Igorots, [114] (Box 2, Tray 3)
    - Igorot girl with jewelry, [115] (Box 2, Tray 3)
    - Igorot spear thrower, [116] (Box 2, Tray 3)
    - Bontocs brass gongs, [117] (Box 2, Tray 3)
    - Igorots, [118] (Box 2, Tray 3)
    - Igorot smokers, [119] (Box 2, Tray 3)
    - Igorot spear thrower, [120] (Box 2, Tray 3)
    - Igorot, [121] (Box 2, Tray 3)
    - Igorot warrior, [122] (Box 2, Tray 3)
    - Igorots carrying pots, [123] (Box 2, Tray 3)
    - Dog tooth headdress (Igorot), [124] (Box 2, Tray 3)
    - Igorot boy, [125] (Box 2, Tray 3)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Formal dress, [126] (Box 2, Tray 3)
    - Formal dress, [127] (Box 2, Tray 3)
    - Filipino entertainer, [128] (Box 2, Tray 3)
    - Tattoo art, [129] (Box 2, Tray 3)
    - Bus in Philippine village, [130] (Box 2, Tray 3)
    - Geisha girls, [131] (Box 2, Tray 3)
    - School children, [132] (Box 2, Tray 3)
    - Mestizo dress, [133] (Box 2, Tray 3)
    - Sculptor--Tolentino?, [134] (Box 2, Tray 3)
    - Christian couple, [135] (Box 2, Tray 3)
    - Escolta, [136] (Box 2, Tray 3)
    - University of Philippines, [137] (Box 2, Tray 3)
    - University of Philippines, [138] (Box 2, Tray 3)
    - Manila Hotel, [139] (Box 2, Tray 3)
    - Manila Hotel, dance, [140] (Box 2, Tray 3)
    - Sun Dial, University of Philippines, [141] (Box 2, Tray 3)
    - Pier 7 Manila, [142] (Box 2, Tray 3)
    - University of Philippines, [143] (Box 2, Tray 3)
    - Government building, Manila, [144] (Box 2, Tray 3)
    - Red Cross workers, [145] (Box 2, Tray 3)
    - Calisthenics, [146] (Box 2, Tray 3)
    - Legislative Building, Manila, [147] (Box 2, Tray 3)
    - Rice, [148] (Box 2, Tray 3)
    - Hemp carrier, [149] (Box 2, Tray 3)
    - Flagellant, [150] (Box 2, Tray 3)
    - National Guard recruits, 1918; [151] (Box 2, Tray 3)
    - Filipino troops--Lineta, Manila, [152] (Box 2, Tray 3)
    - Filipino girls, [153] (Box 2, Tray 4)
  - W. W. Marquardt
    - Gov. Yeater, Sec. Irwin, Marquardt, and Supt. Kelleher, [154] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - Gov. Yeater, Marquardt, and four Bukidnon girls, [155] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - Gov. Yeater and Dr. Marquardt at mansion house, 1919; [156] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - At Bontoc Yeater, Marquardt, 1919; [157] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - Bound for Bontoc--on ferry, 1919-Yeater and Marquardt, [158] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - At the Ato, Bontoc village-1919 Yeater, Marquardt, [159] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - The governor, the Captain, Marquardt, and Sec. Irwin, [160] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - Yeater, Marquardt, and Sec. Irwin at Puerto Princesa, [161] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - Yeater, ?, teacher Doherty, Marquardt, Cudarangan, Cotabao, [162] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - Mrs. Fisher, Gov. Yeater, a Davao chief, Marquardt, and Mr. Moore, [163] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - Gov. Yeater, Marquardt, and three Davao natives, [164] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - Coming into Sagada Yeater, Marquardt, and Skattebol, 1919; [165] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - Gov. Yeater and Marquardt, native section-Sandacan, Borneo, [166] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - Marquardt on "Quantico" wreck, [167] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - Cheney and Marquardt taking it easy on the "Polillo", [168] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - Marquardt and part of fish the shark did not get, [169] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - Mr. Cheney with his big fish and my half, [170] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - Tropical jungle, Robinson and Cheney en route Baler, [171] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - O.C. Hansen with Kalinga. women, [172] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - Magee and Bontoc dancers, [173] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - Magee?, [174] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - The man who struck Jones the first blow, [175] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - The other two Jones murderers, [176] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - Scene of Jones' murder, [177] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - Jones' death staged, [178] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - Borrowing a light, [179] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - Hansen and Marquardt, [180] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - Moss getting folklore, [181] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - Head hunter and his trophies, [182] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - Marquardt and Igorot schoolgirl, [183] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - Marquardt buying curios, Banaue, [184] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - Sultan and party in Office of Director of Education, [185] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - Bamboo Bridge, [186] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - Ex-President Taft, General Edwards, Trade School baseball team, 1906-07, [187] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - The Hon. Manuel Quezon, [188] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - The Hon. Sergio Osmeña, [189] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - Osmeña, [190] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - Quezon, [191] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - Osmeña, [192] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - Mr. and Mrs. Emilio Aguinaldo, 1919; [193] (Box 2, Tray 4)
  - People
    - Apayao men, [194] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - Bagobo woman, [195] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - Bilau men, [196] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - The Queen of the Bicol meet, [197] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - Bontoc trial marriage house, Olag, [198] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - The Council house of a Bontoc village, [199] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - Vaccination among the Bontocs, [200] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - Bontoc War Council, [201] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - Bontoc women hulling rice, [202] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - Bontoc rice gatherers, [203] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - Bontoc warriors, [204] (Box 2, Tray 4)
    - Bontoc headmen, [205] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - Bontoc Charlatan doctor diagnosing a case, [206] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - Bontoc Charlatan (black and white), [207] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - Bontoc mourning ceremony, [208] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - Bontoc Townshouse, [209] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - Bontoc women, [210] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - A meeting of Bontoc headmen, 1912; [211] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - Bontoc girls, [212] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - Bontoc musicians--note human jaws for handles, [213] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - Bontoc dog roast, [214] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - Dog market, Bagnio, [215-216]; 2 slides (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - A dog feast, [217] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - Pee-o-he (Hilario Clapp, also known as Pit-a-Pit). As the Americans found him in his native village of Bontoc, [218] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - Hilario Clapp--a Bontoc, senior in Medicine, 1918; [219] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - Ilongot tree house, [220] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - Ilongot headmen, [221] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - Ilongot warriors, [222] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - An Ilongot man, [223] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - Ilongot Dandy, [224] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - Ilongot Dance, [225] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - Among the Ifugaos, 1918; [226] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - Ifugao rice terraces, [227] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - Ifugao home, [228] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - Ifugao people at home, 1918; [229] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - Ifugao men, [230] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - Ifugao dance, [231] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - Ifugao; chair of state, [232] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - Ifugao, Carabao ceremony--assembly, [233] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - Ifugao, Carabao ceremony--the first rush, [234] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - Ifugao, Carabao ceremony--the final rush, [235] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - Ifugao, Carabao ceremony--placing the animal, [236] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - Ifugao soldier, [237] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - Ifugao dance--first pose, [238] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - Ifugao dance--second pose, [239] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - Ifugao dance--third pose, [240] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - Ifugao belle, [241] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - Learning to sew-Ifugao, [242] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - Kalinga chiefs, [243] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - Kalinga warrior, [244] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - Bagobos in Davao, [245] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - Negrito woman with twins, [246] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - Negrito girls, [247] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - A happy Negrito, [248] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - Manyan women of Mindoro--bark dresses, [249] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - A turn-out in our honor in Iloilo, [250] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - Ilocano women, [251] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - Tinguian women, [252] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - Tinguian nose flute player, [253] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - Tinguian women, [254] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - Tinguian school marm, [255] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - Moro man, [256] (Box 3, Tray 5)
    - A Moro girl's indoor baseball team, 1919; [257] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - Sultan of Sulu and women of his household, [258] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - Sultan Sulu and Harem, [259] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - Interior Moro Datu's Home, [260] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - Moro Datu's Palace, Dansalan, Lanao, [261] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - Raw material, [262] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - Raw material, [263] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - Indoor baseball game at Parañaque, Rizal Province, [264] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - Indoor baseball game on the "home grounds", [265] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - Old time opium den, Manila, 1901; [266] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - Mestiza girl, [267] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - Stride, Tondo Public Playground, Manila, [268] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - Two old types of dress, Philippine Islands, [269] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - Washwomen, [270] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - Embroidery worker, 1918; [271] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - A water carrier, [272] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - Moro head dress, [273] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - Moro fishing village, Sulu, [274] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - Manobo bad men and their captor, [275] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - Bacod schoolgirls with musical instruments, [276] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - Native weavers, Bontoc, [277] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - Indoor baseball, Bontoc, [278] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - Igorot cargadores, [279] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - A scramble for pennies, [280] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - Bontoc bride and groom, [281] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - Igorot girls--front view, [282] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - Bontoc Igorot--rear view, [283] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - Igorot girls--rear view, [284] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - Igorot woman with child, [285] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - Igorot man, [286] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - Ifugao man and woman, [287] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - Pablo and Umo, Ilongot chiefs, [288] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - Calao headdress, Ilongot mark of valor, [289] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - Two Ilongot schoolgirls, [290] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - Three Ilongot schoolboys, [291] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - An Ilongot woman and daughters, [292] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - An Ilongot house at Campote, [293] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - An Ilongot family at Campote, [294] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - Entrance to Ilongot house, [295] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - Building a raft on the upper Cagayan, [296] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - Negrito schoolgirls at Calabgan, [297] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - Negrito schoolboys at Calabgan, [298] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - Making soldiers from Igorots, [299] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - Threshing rice by treading, [300] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - Baptism of Carabao, early Surigao picture, [301] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - Rewarding a prisoner for bravery, San Ramon Prison, [302] (Box 3, Tray 6)
  - Schools
    - A primitive school room, [303] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - An early school, 1919--learning to write, [304] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - An early school in Bontoc, [305] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - Light material school building, [306] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - Teacher's cottage, Sulu, 1919; [307] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - Spanish type school building, Moac, Marinduque, [308] (Box 3, Tray 6)
    - A school in the Moro country, [309] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - Normal hall, dormitory, [310] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - Dormitory group, Philippine Normal School, Manila, [311] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - 1st Day at Bua School near Bagnio, [312] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - 2nd week at Bua School for Igorot girls, [313] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - At the Bua school for Igorot girls near teacher's camp, Bagnio, [314] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - Group of pupils in one of public schools, [315] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - A lanao school--three children with smallpox, [316] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - Ilongot school girls--cloth for dresses woven locally, [317] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - Class in sewing in a provincial school, [318] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - Slipper making at public school, [319] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - Moro School at exercises, [320] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - School desks and schoolboys at P.S.A.T., [321] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - Domestic science instruction--setting the table, [322] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - Maguey school garden, Siquijor, [323] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - Two indoor baseball players, [324] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - Folk dances; Playground Day, Carnival, 1914; [325] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - Playground Day, Manila, 1919--folk dancers, [326] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - Playground Day, Manila, 1919--assembly, [327] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - Mrs. Moss and schoolgirls, Bontoc, [328] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - School, [329] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - School girls making lace, Bontoc, [330] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - Rose instructing Igorot mothers, [331] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - School dormitories, Maquebenga, [332] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - Camote (sweet potato) field at settlement farm school, [333] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - School garden, Lucena, Tayabas, [334] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - Plan #1--school building Salinas, Cavite, [335] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - School girls and building, Bakod., [336] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - Scene from school Play, Manila, [337] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - Another scene from school play, [338] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - Learning to dance, Bua school girls, [339] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - Indoor baseball team and teachers, Cebu, [340] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - Sulu Princesses in old dress, [341] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - Sulu Princesses after entering school, [342] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - First aid work in school dispensary, Mindanao, [343] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - Bureau of Science Building, Manila, [344] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - A lesson in cooking, [345] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - Interior Court, School of Arts and Trades, [346] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - Modern Concrete School Building, [347] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - A class recitation, [348] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - A school orchestra, [349] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - A school library, [350] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - Munoz schoolboys threshing rice, [351] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - Parade of athletes, Insular School Meet, [352] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - Students using a school library, [353] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - Preparing for garden day, [354] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - Two poultry club members, [355] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - School boys making concrete fence posts, [356] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - A class in surveying, [357] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - High hurdle race, [358] (Box 4, Tray 7)
    - Old block house--Teachers' quarters, Piang Agriculture School, [359] (Box 4, Tray 7)
- Correspondence, diaries, speeches, etc.
  - Bound copies of correspondence, diaries, speeches, writings, reports, etc. (Box 5)
  - Bound copies of correspondence, diaries, speeches, writings, reports, etc. (Box 6)
    (continued)
  - Bound copies of correspondence, diaries, speeches, writings, reports, etc. (Box 7)
- Miscellaneous
  - Biographical (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, 1919-1921 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence, 1942-1952; undated (Box 7)
  - Papers relating to Philippine education (Box 7)
  - Papers relating to Philippines (Box 7)
  - Portraits (Box 7)